A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Office of Communications, Advisor on Communications, Office Files of Fred W. Friendly FA616
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Subjects, 1958-1980; VI; 6.6 Cubic Feet
  - Communications Sattelite Corporation (COMSAT), 1966 - 1967 (Box 16 (34796), Folder 29)
  - Community News Service, 1969 (Box 16 (34796), Folder 30)
  - Community Antenna Television (CATV, cable television), 1966 - 1969 (Box 16 (34796), Folder 31)
  - Community Antenna Television, 1970 - 1972 (Box 17 (34797), Folder 1-6)
  - Community Antenna Television – New York City policy, 1970 - 1972 (Box 17 (34797), Folder 7)
  - Conference on Impact of Media on Political Campaigning, circa 1972 (Box 17 (34797), Folder 8)
  - Consultants, 1976 - 1978 (Box 17 (34797), Folder 9)
  - Corporation for Public Broadcasting, 1968 - 1978 (Box 17 (34797), Folder 10-12)
  - Drugs, 1971 (Box 17 (34797), Folder 13)
  - Educational Journalism Fellowship, 1975 - 1976 (Box 17 (34797), Folder 14)
  - Educational Television, 1962 - 1963 (Box 17 (34797), Folder 15)
  - Edward R. Murrow Park, 1979 (Box 17 (34797), Folder 16)
  - Europe trip, 1961 (Box 17 (34797), Folder 17)
  - Executive privilege, 1971 - 1973 (Box 17 (34797), Folder 18-20)
  - Fairness doctrine, 1972 - 1975 (Box 17 (34797), Folder 21)
  - Federal Communications Commission (FCC) – Loevinger, Lee, 1966 - 1967 (Box 17 (34797), Folder 22)
  - Ford Foundation 25th Anniversary project, 1974 (Box 17 (34797), Folder 23)
  - Future program planning project, 1976 (Box 17 (34797), Folder 24)
  - George Foster Peabody Award, 1959 - 1965 (Box 17 (34797), Folder 25)
  - Godkin Lectures, 1969 (Box 17 (34797), Folder 26)
  - Hartke Hearings – U.S. Senate, 1974 (Box 17 (34797), Folder 27)
  - Hoffman, Abbie, 1975 (Box 17 (34797), Folder 28)
  - Human rights and the news media, 1976 - 1978 (Box 17 (34797), Folder 29)
  - I Can Hear It Now, 1958 (Box 17 (34797), Folder 30)
  - Information industry, 1968 (Box 17 (34797), Folder 31)
  - Institute for American Strategy, 1972 - 1975 (Box 18 (34863), Folder 1)
  - Instructional television, 1966 - 1969 (Box 18 (34863), Folder 2)
  - Instructional Television Centre, undated (Box 18 (34863), Folder 3)
  - International Broadcast Institute, 1974 - 1975 (Box 18 (34863), Folder 4-5)
  - International Institute for Educational Planning, 1966 (Box 18 (34863), Folder 6-7)
  - International Press Institute – 25th General Assembly, 1976 (Box 18 (34863), Folder 8)
  - International Press Institute – 28th General Assembly, 1979 (Box 18 (34863), Folder 9-11)
  - Japan, 1970 - 1972 (Box 18 (34863), Folder 12)
  - Kleegman, Sophia J., 1970 - 1973 (Box 18 (34863), Folder 13)
  - Media and Business Seminars, 1977 - 1980 (Box 18 (34863), Folder 14)
  - Media seminars – miscellaneous, 1978 - 1980 (Box 18 (34863), Folder 15)
  - Mid-Career Fellowship Program for Journalists, 1974 - 1979 (Box 18 (34863), Folder 16-18)
  - National Black Network, 1970 (Box 18 (34863), Folder 19)
  - National District Attorney's Association, 1978 (Box 18 (34863), Folder 20)
  - National Educational Television (NET), 1965 - 1966 (Box 18 (34863), Folder 21-22)
  - NET, 1970 - 1971 (Box 19 (34869), Folder 1)
  - NET – "America's Crises: Trouble in the Family", 1965 - 1966 (Box 19 (34869), Folder 2)
  - NET – proposals, 1966 - 1969 (Box 19 (34869), Folder 3)
  - National Programming Council for Public Television, 1971 - 1972 (Box 19 (34869), Folder 4)
  - News clippings regarding Friendly, 1960s - 1970s (Box 19 (34869), Folder 5)
  - Newsroom – reports, 1970 (Box 19 (34869), Folder 6-7)
  - Office of Communications – budget, 1978 - 1980 (Box 19 (34869), Folder 8)
  - Office of Communications – fiscal status reports, 1975 - 1980 (Box 19 (34869), Folder 9)
  - Office of Communications – reports, 1970s (Box 19 (34869), Folder 10)
  - Office of Public Broadcasting – fiscal status reports, 1971 - 1974 (Box 19 (34869), Folder 11)
  - Office of Public Broadcasting – reports, 1967 - 1973 (Box 19 (34869), Folder 12)
  - Patterson, John Meredith, 1975 (Box 19 (34869), Folder 13)
  - Plays for the Living, 1966 - 1967 (Box 19 (34869), Folder 14)
  - Project for New Television Programming - Correspondence, 1968 - 1969 (Box 19 (34869), Folder 15)
  - Project for New Television Programming - Miscellaneous, 1968 - 1969 (Box 19 (34869), Folder 16-17)
  - Project for New Television Programming - Proposals, 1968 (Box 19 (34869), Folder 18-20)
  - Public Broadcast Laboratory - Bass, Milton R., 1967 (Box 19 (34869), Folder 21)
  - Public Broadcast Laboratory - Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, 1967 (Box 19 (34869), Folder 22)
  - Public Broadcast Laboratory - Colleges and universities, miscellaneous, 1966 - 1967 (Box 19 (34869), Folder 23)
  - Public Broadcast Laboratory - Columbia University, 1966 - 1967 (Box 19 (34869), Folder 24)
  - Public Broadcast Laboratory - General, 1966 - 1969 (Box 19 (34869), Folder 25-27)
  - Public Broadcast Laboratory - NET, 1967 (Box 19 (34869), Folder 28)
  - Public Broadcast Laboratory - Staffing, 1967 (Box 19 (34869), Folder 29)
  - Public Broadcast Laboratory - Westin, Av, 1966 - 1968 (Box 19 (34869), Folder 30)
  - Public radio network, 1967 - 1970 (Box 20 (34949), Folder 1)
  - Public relations, 1971 (Box 20 (34949), Folder 2)
  - Public Telecommunications Financing Act, 1978 (Box 20 (34949), Folder 3)
  - Public Television Audience Research Working Seminar, 1971 (Box 20 (34949), Folder 4)
  - Research, miscellaneous, 1969 (Box 20 (34949), Folder 5)
  - San Francisco Palace of Fine Arts, 1969 (Box 20 (34949), Folder 6)
  - Satellite proposal – drafts, 1966 (Box 20 (34949), Folder 7-10)
  - Satellite proposal – memos, 1966 - 1967 (Box 20 (34949), Folder 11-13)
  - Satellite proposal – press release, 1966 (Box 20 (34949), Folder 14)
  - Satellite Task Force, 1969 - 1972 (Box 20 (34949), Folder 15-16)
  - Satellites – general, 1969 - 1970 (Box 20 (34949), Folder 17)
  - Scalia, Antonin, 1971 - 1972 (Box 20 (34949), Folder 18)
  - School desegregation film, 1978 (Box 20 (34949), Folder 19)
  - See It Now – transcripts, 1955 - 1958 (Box 20 (34949), Folder 20)
  - Seminar on Children and Television Violence, 1978 (Box 20 (34949), Folder 21)
  - Smothers Brothers, 1969 (Box 20 (34949), Folder 22)
  - Station Independence Project, 1972 - 1978 (Box 20 (34949), Folder 23-24)
  - Station visits, 1968 - 1971 (Box 20 (34949), Folder 25)
  - Tax reform, 1969 (Box 20 (34949), Folder 26)
  - Telecommunications Cooperative Network, 1978 (Box 20 (34949), Folder 27)
  - Telecommunications Task Force, 1971 - 1973 (Box 20 (34949), Folder 28-29)
  - Television in the Courthouse, 1978 - 1980 (Box 20 (34949), Folder 30)
  - Tornillo, Pat L., 1973 - 1974 (Box 21 (35020), Folder 1)
  - Tydings, Joseph C., 1967 (Box 21 (35020), Folder 2)
  - United Church of Christ, 1977 (Box 21 (35020), Folder 3)
  - U.S. Congress – televised proceedings, 1978 - 1979 (Box 21 (35020), Folder 4)
  - U.S. House of Representatives Committee on Interstate and Foreign Commerce Subcommittee on Communications and Power, 1973 (Box 21 (35020), Folder 5)
  - U.S. House of Representatives – House Gallery, 1971 (Box 21 (35020), Folder 6)
  - U.S. Virgin Islands Public Television, 1968 - 1969 (Box 21 (35020), Folder 7)
  - U.S. Vision One, 1966 (Box 21 (35020), Folder 8)
  - Washington Post Conference on Media and Government, 1980 (Box 21 (35020), Folder 9)
  - WETA (Washington D.C.) – Woestendiek firing, 1970 (Box 21 (35020), Folder 10)
  - Whitehead, Clay T., 1971 - 1974 (Box 21 (35020), Folder 11)
  - WNET – program evaluations, 1973 - 1974 (Box 21 (35020), Folder 12)
- Writings, 1956-1979; VII; 1.8 Cubic Feet
  Published and unpublished articles and monographs authored by Friendly. Most articles are commentaries on the television industry and telecommunications policy. Many files contain correspondence with publishers and reader, publicity materials, reviews and research materials pertaining to the publication. Topics include freedom of the press, media policy and public television finance.
  Files are arranged alphabetically by title.
  - "Asleep at the Switch of the Wired City," Saturday Review, 1970 October 10 (Box 21 (35020), Folder 13)
  - "Bakke, Unmuddy," New York Times, 1978 June 15 (Box 21 (35020), Folder 14)
  - [BBC and broadcast journalism], 1972 (Box 21 (35020), Folder 15)
  - "The Bitter Heritage of Nixon," Boston Globe, 1974 August 12 (Box 21 (35020), Folder 16)
  - "The campaign to politicize broadcasting," Columbia Journalism Review, 1973 March - April (Box 21 (35020), Folder 17)
  - "The Case Against the Evening News", undated (Box 21 (35020), Folder 18)
  - "The Common Stock vs. the Commonweal", undated (Box 21 (35020), Folder 19)
  - "The Court on Press Gags: Not Worth It," New York Times, 1976 July 4 (Box 21 (35020), Folder 20)
  - "Crisis Reporting and Relativity", undated (Box 21 (35020), Folder 21)
  - "Dear Jack Gould, They Say You've Retired...," New York Times, 1972 February 27 (Box 21 (35020), Folder 22)
  - Due to Circumstances Beyond Our Control - Correspondence, 1966 - 1969 (Box 21 (35020), Folder 23-25)
  - Due to Circumstances Beyond Our Control - Speaking engagements, 1967 (Box 22 (35175), Folder 1-2)
  - Due to Circumstances Beyond Our Control - Typescript, 1966 (Box 22 (35175), Folder 3)
  - "A 45-Year-Old Rivet in the First Amendment," New York Times, 1976 June 9 (Box 22 (35175), Folder 4)
  - "From intense tennis in Stockbridge to intensive care at BMC", circa 1978 (Box 22 (35175), Folder 5)
  - The Good Guys, the Bad Guys and the First Amendment: Free Speech vs. Fairness in Broadcasting - Correspondence, 1974 - 1976 (Box 22 (35175), Folder 6)
  - The Good Guys, the Bad Guys and the First Amendment: Free Speech vs. Fairness in Broadcasting - Research materials, 1960s - 1970s (Box 22 (35175), Folder 7-9)
  - "Government Plan: 'Chilling,'" U.S. News and World Report, 1973 February 19 (Box 22 (35175), Folder 10)
  - "'Holocaust,' 9 ½ Hours Later," Washington Post, 1978 April 23 (Box 22 (35175), Folder 11)
  - "The judiciary on trial," Boston Sunday Globe, 1978 March 26 (Box 22 (35175), Folder 12)
  - "Justice White and reporter Caldwell: finding a common ground," Columbia Journalism Review, 1972 September - October (Box 22 (35175), Folder 13)
  - "McGraw-Hill and a Free Press," The Wall Street Journal, 1979 January 26 (Box 22 (35175), Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous, 1960s (Box 22 (35175), Folder 15)
  - "Murder in Nebraska," Dateline '77, 1977 (Box 22 (35175), Folder 16)
  - "Must the Industry Be Ruled by 'The Numbers,'" New York Times, 1978 August 6 (Box 22 (35175), Folder 17)
  - "Paying the High Price of a President In an Isolation Booth," New York, 1973 June 11 (Box 22 (35175), Folder 18)
  - "Public TV must operate under handicap," Louisville Times, 1967 August 15 (Box 22 (35175), Folder 19)
  - "The Public's Right to Know," The Wall Street Journal, 1978 October 5 (Box 22 (35175), Folder 20)
  - "South Africa in Transition: Review", 1956 (Box 22 (35175), Folder 21)
  - "Television and the First Amendment," Saturday Review, 1972 January 8 (Box 22 (35175), Folder 22)
  - "This … is Murrow," Saturday Review, 1969 September 27 (Box 22 (35175), Folder 23)
  - "Trying to keep Henry Kissinger out of Columbia," The Sunday Sun, 1977 May 29 (Box 22 (35175), Folder 24)
  - "TV at the turning point," Columbia Journalism Review, 1970 - 1971 Winter (Box 22 (35175), Folder 25)
  - "The unselling of The Selling of the Pentagon," Harper's, 1971 June (Box 22 (35175), Folder 26)
  - "We Offer Our Activism, Our Faith...," New York Times, 1970 May 31 (Box 22 (35175), Folder 27)
  - "What's Fair on the Air," New York Times Magazine, 1975 March 30 (Box 22 (35175), Folder 28)